<!--
  @author Reika Kalseki
  
  Copyright 2018
  
  All rights reserved.
  Distribution of the software in any form is only allowed with
  explicit, prior permission from the owner.
-->
<?xml version="1.0"?>
<info>
	<physics>
		Nuclear reactions fall into two main types, fission and fusion. Each of these works off of Einstein's theory of relativity to generate energy from mass - E = mc^2. This energy is released as heat or as a speeding neutron. Because the value of c (the speed of light) is extremely large - 300 million meters per second - the amount of energy released is often very large, even though the mass consumption is tiny.
	</physics>
	<fissioninfo>
		In nuclear fission, a heavy atom, such as that of uranium or plutonium, is impacted with an extra neutron. This destabilizes it, and the atom soon splits into two others, releasing a large amount of energy in the process. This reaction also releases three more neutrons, which can impact three more atoms and trigger a chain reaction. The two resultant atoms are usually unwanted and hazardous waste products.
	</fissioninfo>
	<fusioninfo>
		In nuclear fusion, two light atoms, usually hydrogen, are forced together under extreme heat and pressure until they join together. Some mass is lost in this process, releasing heat and a speeding neutron. This neutron carries a large amount of the energy from this reaction and must be captured to regain that energy. Unlike fission, fusion cannot create a chain reaction, and produces no waste, but it is much more difficult to accomplish. Most artificial fusion reactors use two hydrogen isotopes, deuterium and tritium.
	</fusioninfo>
	<basics>
		Nuclear power plants work in fundamentally the same way as most others; the nuclear reaction generates heat, which is eventually used to boil water into steam. This steam drives a turbine and generates shaft power. Nuclear fuel is consumed rather slowly compared to most others, but it is often difficult to produce and its after-effects are often difficult to dispose of.
	</basics>
	<enrichment>
		Uranium comes in two main varieties, U235 and U238. Only U235 is immediately useful for nuclear power, but it makes up less than 1%% of all uranium, with the rest being U238. For this reason, uranium is 'enriched', where the concentration of U235 is increased to usable levels. The U238 left over, sometimes termed 'depleted uranium', can be bombarded with neutrons to convert it into Pu239, a form of plutonium also usable in fission reactors, though with more risk and worse waste products. Depleted uranium can also be used to make high-density objects.
	</enrichment>
	<meltdown>
	If a reactor gets too hot, it will start to boil off its coolant and emit large quantities of smoke and steam. Hotter still, and it may cause the water molecules to break apart, resulting in a large accumulation of hydrogen gas. Because hydrogen gas is flammable, it can often result in an explosion that sends pieces of the reactor in all directions. Additionally, the fuel and steel structure of the fuel core itself will soften, melt and mix into a lavalike fluid called "corium", which is intensely radioactive. Meltdowns spread extreme radiation over a fairly large area.
	</meltdown>
	<radiation>
		Radioactivity is a dangerous property of many nuclear materials, as it will severely poison living things. Low-level radioactivity is not immediately lethal, but it can bring about unpleasant effects such as dizziness and nausea. Higher levels of radioactivity, such as those left behind after a nuclear meltdown, will kill in fairly short order. Radioactivity leaves a distinctive mark on the land, killing plants, grass, and and animals alike. Radiation cannot be cleaned manually, but will gradually decay over time, and can be washed away by rain.
	</radiation>
	<shielding>
		Most reactors fire out high-energy neutrons that can harm or kill living things, and to this end it is almost universally advisable to shield such a reactor. Additionally, should a meltdown occur, proper shielding can limit both structural damage and the spread of lethal levels of radiation. Only a few block types are effective in this regard.
	</shielding>
	<structures>
		Nuclear reactors and their parts are often large, far larger than the cubic meter in which most machines will fit. Additionally, they are often comprised of many individual parts which only form a coherent whole in a specific arrangement.
	</structures>
</info>
