<!--
  @author Reika Kalseki
  
  Copyright 2018
  
  All rights reserved.
  Distribution of the software in any form is only allowed with
  explicit, prior permission from the owner.
-->
<?xml version="1.0"?>
<machines>
	<processor>
		<desc>
			The uranium processor dissolves fluorite in water to make hydrofluoric acid, and then dissolves raw uranium in the acid to make uranium hexafluoride gas. This gas is used in the uranium enrichment process.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Does not require power
			Requires a water supply
		</note>
	</processor>
	<centrifuge>
		<desc>
			The isotope centrifuge uses a very high rotational speed to separate the different isotopes of uranium, and will produce a mixture of depleted uranium dust and enriched uranium dust. The latter is far less common due to the rarity of U235.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Minimum Speed: %d rad/s
			Power Input: Bottom
			UF6 Input: Top
		</note>
	</centrifuge>
	<electrolyzer>
		<desc>
			The electrolyzer uses electrical discharges to decompose materials into their constituents, such as salt into sodium and chlorine or water into hydrogen and oxygen. The heavier of the products is drawn from the bottom, while the lighter is drawn from the top. Note that solids must be melted down before they are able to be processed.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Required temperature to melt salt: %dC
		</note>
	</electrolyzer>
	<synthesizer>
		<desc>
			The synthesizer is primarily used to make ammonia, which is a more effective working fluid in reactors than water. To do this, it requires water, ammonium chloride, and quicklime. It can also process a few other fluids.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Ammonia Synthesis Temperature: %dC
		</note>
	</synthesizer>
	<tritizer>
		<desc>
			The neutron irradiation chamber converts deuterium to tritium by bombarding it with neutrons. This machine is placed in the core of a reactor, where it will absorb some neutrons that hit it and convert the stored deuterium.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Deuterium Input: Top
			Tritium Output: Bottom
		</note>
	</tritizer>
	<condenser>
		<desc>
			The condenser will recollect steam blocks and convert it back into liquid for reuse in the nuclear reactor. Because the pressure is extremely low, this liquid must be repressurized before it can be used. While it may not be terribly economical to reclaim water-based steam, ammonia is sufficiently expensive that reclamation is well worth the cost.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Liquid Output: Top
		</note>
	</condenser>
	<exchanger>
		<desc>
			The heat exchanger takes hot fluid in the top and cools it down, transferring the fluid's heat into any adjacent machinery, including standard boilers. This machine requires power to force the fluid through, and the fluid can be drawn out the sides.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Power Input: Bottom:
			Required Power: %dW
			Required Speed: %d rad/s
		</note>
	</exchanger>
	<boiler>
		<desc>
			The boiler absorbs heat from the surrounding machines and uses it to boil the internal liquid into steam. Note that if the steam is not drawn away and allowed to accumulate, the boiler will eventually lose the ability to boil more liquid and fail to draw away heat from the reactor. This usually results in a meltdown. Also, if the temperature rises above %dC when the boiler is full of ammonia, the ammonia will ignite and detonate.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Liquid Input: Bottom:
			Steam Output: Top
		</note>
	</boiler>
	<pump>
		<desc>
			The pressurizer repressurizes the low-pressure water or ammonia so that it can be reused in the reactor, thus completing the thermodynamic cycle. Note that this is a centrifugal compressor.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Minimum Power: %dW
			Minimum Torque: %d Nm
			Liquid Input: Top
			Liquid Output: Side
			Power Input: Bottom
		</note>
	</pump>
	<grate>
		<desc>
			The steam grate takes in steam from steam lines and releases it into the world. The steam will then rise until it hits a blockage, where it will spread out. Ideally, the steam should rise directly into a turbine so that its energy can be extracted.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Steam Output: Top
			Max Ouput: 1 block per tick (20 blocks/s)
		</note>
	</grate>
	<steamline>
		<desc>
			Steam lines transport the steam away from the reactor to a turbine. Note that the steam line has an infinite capacity and thus breaking it may result in a loss of a large amount of stored energy.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Infinite capacity
		</note>
	</steamline>
	<turbinecore>
		<desc>
			The turbine extracts the energy from steam, which moves along its length. The turbine will gradually accelerate as it receives steam, and its torque will be proportional to the amount of steam flowing through. Note that turbines, especially if rotating rapidly, are extremely fragile. The turbine will not run if its blades are obstructed.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Max Speed: %d rad/s
			Max Torque: %d Nm
			Risks: Blade breakage due to collisions with objects
			Turbines require lubrication
		</note>
	</turbinecore>
	<pebblebed>
		<desc>
			The pebble bed reactor core is the fuel unit for a pebble bed reactor. Load it up with fuel pellets, and it will undergo spontaneous fission and generate heat. This heat is best transferred to a carbon dioxide heat exchanger.
		</desc>
		<note>

		</note>
	</pebblebed>
	<co2heater>
		<desc>
			The CO2 Heat Exchanger absorbs heat from a pebble bed reactor and transfers it into the carbon dioxide pumped in. The hot carbon dioxide can be drawn out the top and fed into a heat exchanger.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Must reach 800C to emit hot carbon dioxide
		</note>
	</co2heater>
	<fuel>
		<desc>
			The fuel core stores the nuclear fuel and is the source of all nuclear reactions and heat generation. When loaded, the core will periodically emit neutrons, which can impact other fuel cores. If those cores are also loaded, there is a chance that they will undergo fission, releasing three more neutrons and some heat, and consume some fuel. They will also gradually accumulate waste, which will hamper their ability to undergo fission. If the fuel core gets too hot, it will begin smoking, releasing hydrogen gas, and will eventually melt and release large amounts of radiation.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Neutron Emission: Any horizontal direction
			Max Temperature: %dC
		</note>
	</fuel>
	<control>
		<desc>
			The control rod allows you to manipulate the rate of a nuclear reaction by intercepting neutrons that could otherwise trigger more fission events. Control rods can be retracted or inserted - they are inserted by default - when commanded by a reactor CPU. They also can be dropped into place in the case of an emergency, a so-called "SCRAM" event.
		</desc>
		<note>

		</note>
	</control>
	<coolant>
		<desc>
			Coolant cells draw away heat from the reactor. Note that this heat is essentially wasted, as it does not create any steam or useful energy. However, coolant cells are vital for distributing heat and stabilizing the temperature of larger reactors.
		</desc>
		<note>

		</note>
	</coolant>
	<cpu>
		<desc>
			The reactor CPU can be used to manage the operation of a nuclear reactor. It allows you to manipulate each control rod individually, or all at once. It also will sense the temperature of the surroundings and will trigger a SCRAM if the temperature gets too high, preventing a meltdown. Note that much as in a real reactor, if the CPU loses power for any reason, the control rods will all fall into place, likely stopping the nuclear reaction.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Power Per Control Rod: %dW
		</note>
	</cpu>
	<breeder>
		<desc>
			The breeder reactor core behaves much like the normal fuel core, but can only accept breeder reactor fuel, and is the only type of reactor core that can be used in a breeder reactor. They heat up somewhat faster than normal uranium-fueled cores.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Neutron Emission: Any horizontal direction
			Max Temperature: %dC
		</note>
	</breeder>
	<sodiumboiler>
		<desc>
			The sodium heater will, much like a steam boiler, accumulate heat from the surroundings and heat up liquid pumped through it. However, it only accepts molten sodium and will output hot molten sodium once its temperature reaches 300 degrees. This hot molten sodium is usable in a heat exchanger.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Sodium Input: Bottom
			Hot Sodium Output: Top
		</note>
	</sodiumboiler>
	<heater>
		<desc>
			The hydrogen preheater uses the beam from the heat ray to heat a mixture of deuterium and tritium into a plasma usable in the fusion reactor. Note that it must be contained in a proper heater unit multiblock structure, and must be in the path of a heat ray beam.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Plasma Temperature: %dC
			Hydrogen Input: Any horizontal side
			Plasma Output: Top
		</note>
	</heater>
	<injector>
		<desc>
			The plasma injector actually injects the fusion plasma into the tokamak reactor. Note that it must be contained in a proper multiblock structure.
		</desc>
		<note>

		</note>
	</injector>
	<magnet>
		<desc>
			The toroidal magnets are the main component of the tokamak reactor, and contain the plasma into a narrow beam in their center. In order to function properly, they must be placed and rotated correctly, and kept very cold.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Can not be placed on flat ground due to large size
		</note>
	</magnet>
	<solenoid>
		<desc>
			The solenoid magnet is the other main component of the tokamak reactor. It bends the plasma beam into a circle, allowing it to be contained and to reach the critical density for fusion to take place. If this magnet is not functional, the plasma beam will shoot off in a random direction. The solenoid is another large multiblock, and requires power to rotate.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Minimum Speed: %d rad/s
			Minimum Torque: %d Nm
			Maximum Speed: %d rad/s
		</note>
	</solenoid>
	<absorber>
		<desc>
			Neutron absorbers intercept neutrons and turn their kinetic energy into heat. Much like a heat exchanger, this heat can be transferred into adjacent machines.
		</desc>
		<note>

		</note>
	</absorber>
	<collector>
		<desc>
			The gas collector collects carbon dioxide from a furnace burning coal or wood. This carbon dioxide is used as the working fluid in high-temperature gas reactors.
		</desc>
		<note>

		</note>
	</collector>
	<gaspipe>
		<desc>
			Gas Ducts are used to transport gas, and are made of clay so as not to react with corrosive gases like hydrofluoric acid and uranium hexafluoride.
		</desc>
		<note>

		</note>
	</gaspipe>
	<magnetpipe>
		<desc>
			Magnetic containment pipes are used to transport extremely hot gases. They use a magnetic field to keep the contents away from the walls, as the pipe would otherwise melt. Note that an electrical charge must be applied to the pipe for it to work.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Requires charge from a Van De Graaff
		</note>
	</magnetpipe>
	<heavypump>
		<desc>
			Heavy water is a special type of water that contains deuterium in place of hydrogen. Deuterium is more dense than hydrogen and thus heavy water exists in small quantities at the bottom of large bodies of water. The heavy water extractor's purpose is to separate the heavy water from the normal water near the ocean floor. Due to heavy water's natural density, this can only occur in an ocean biome below y = 45, and the extractor will only function if it has at least 16 source blocks of water above it and it is surrounded on three other sides by water.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Minimum Power: %dW
			Minimum Torque: %d Nm
		</note>
	</heavypump>
	<fluidextractor>
		<desc>
			The fluid extractor, when submerged in and surrounded by source blocks of a fluid, can centrifuge it and obtain trace quantities of another fluid that was mixed in. For example, heavy water can be centrifuged out of the bottom of oceans (below y=%d and with at least %dm of water above), or molten lithium can be skimmed off the surface of lava.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Minimum Power: %dW
			Minimum Torque: %d Nm
		</note>
	</fluidextractor>
	<wastecontainer>
		<desc>
			The spent fuel container is the first disposal unit for nuclear waste. When placed in this container, the more radioactive nuclear waste with shorter half-lives will decay and generate heat and neutrons in the process. To keep the container cool, and to provide radiation shielding, it must be submerged underwater.
		</desc>
		<note>

		</note>
	</wastecontainer>
	<storage>
		<desc>
			Longer-lived nuclear waste which will not decay in the spent fuel container must be placed in a waste disposal drum, where it may be safely stored underground indefinitely without risk of overheating or a radiation leak. Note that being in close proximity to a loaded container is still extremely dangerous. Waste with half-lives shorter than six years cannot be safely stored in this machine, as they generate too much heat.
		</desc>
		<note>

		</note>
	</storage>
	<reflector>
		<desc>
			The neutron reflector has a chance of reflecting neutrons back in the direction from which they impacted the reflector. This allows for greater reactor efficiency by reusing a portion of the neutrons. Unreflected neutrons have a chance to be absorbed.
		</desc>
		<note>

		</note>
	</reflector>
	<generator>
		<desc>
			The generator convers shaft power directly from a turbine into other forms of power for ease of transport or use in other mods. Note that it is a multiblock that must be directly connected to the turbine. Also be aware that the extreme power supply this generator provides exceeds the capacities of many transport systems.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Converted Output: Back
			
			Can be mode-switched with the screwdriver
		</note>
	</generator>
	<bigturbine>
		<desc>
			The high-pressure turbine runs off of steam directly from the lines thanks to a built-in steam injection system, allowing it to run more efficiently and generate far more power. Due to the greatly increased size of this turbine, it requires far more steam to operate, and can be built to seven stages instead of five. This turbine also has a housing to prevent damage. Low-pressure liquid can be collected with reservoirs or BC tanks below the back of the turbine.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Max Speed: %d rad/s
			
			Can be disabled with a redstone input to any of the injector blocks
		</note>
	</bigturbine>
	<turbinemeter>
		<desc>
			The turbine dynamometer measures the speed of a turbine. It is placed below the body of a turbine, and will, with the aid of a redstone comparator, output a signal level corresponding to the turbine's speed as a fraction of its maximum speed.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Must be placed below the turbine with a clear view above
			Redstone signal level (Normal Turbine): (Speed/%d)*15
			Redstone signal level (High-Pressure Turbine): (Speed/%d)*15
		</note>
	</turbinemeter>
	<marker>
		<desc>
			The tokamak blueprint highligher provides a general outline of the various parts of a tokamak fusion reactor to help with correctly placing and rotating the various components.
		</desc>
		<note>

		</note>
	</marker>
	<flywheel>
		<desc>
			The turbine flywheel stabilizes the power output of a low-pressure turbine.
		</desc>
		<note>

		</note>
	</flywheel>
	<diffuser>
		<desc>
			The steam diffuser takes hot, high-pressure steam from a reactor boiler and expands and cools it to more conventional lower-pressure steam for use in conventional steam turbines designed for use with coal boilers.
		</desc>
		<note>

		</note>
	</diffuser>
	<thorium>
		<desc>
			Thorium reactor cores use molten thorium fuel salts (Thorium-enriched FLiBe) to generate electricity. Rather unique compared to other fission reactors, they are not self-sufficient and require heat and neutron flux in order to start. Additionally, the temperature-dependent neutron fertility means that as the temperature rises, they become less reactive, as a natural safeguard. The thorium fuel cycle also produces less waste than that of uranium.
		</desc>
		<note>

		</note>
	</thorium>
	<fueldump>
		<desc>
			In the event of exceeding a critical temperature of %dC, a thorium reactor will trigger an emergency fuel dump in order to avoid a meltdown. This can cause a radiation leak, and is to be avoided if possible.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Placed below the fuel column, and will trigger automatically to perform a dump
		</note>
	</fueldump>
	<solartop>
		<desc>
			The %s allows you to use molten sodium instead of water in the solar tower, which greatly increases its power output and efficiency.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Two units must be stacked on top of the tower to function
		</note>
	</solartop>
	<solar>
		<desc>
			The %s allows you to get hot molten sodium out of a solar plant instead of direct shaft power. Though this is more complex, the power output is substantially larger.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Placed below the tower column
			Requires %dW at %d rad/s
		</note>
	</solar>
	<wastedecayer>
		<desc>
			The forced fission chamber is used to bombard nuclear waste with neutrons to encourage it to fragment into products which are more easily disposed of than the original isotopes.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Operates most efficiently around %dC and with fast neutrons (if enabled)
		</note>
	</wastedecayer>
	<name>
		<desc>
			
		</desc>
		<note>
			
		</note>
	</name>
	<name>
		<desc>
			
		</desc>
		<note>
			
		</note>
	</name>
	<name>
		<desc>
			
		</desc>
		<note>
			
		</note>
	</name>
</machines>
